Cameron Bentley

cjbentle@edu.uwaterloo.ca | 587-703-6830

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

BASC IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING Expected 2021 | Waterloo, ON

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Experienced C++ • VBA • Bash • HTML

Basic Knowledge

Python • JavaScript • CSS • Git Versioning

CAD/TECHNICAL DRAFTING

CAD & Markup Software SolidWorks • AutoCAD • Fusion 360 • BlueBeam Revu

Competencies GD&T • P&IDs • DFM

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION

Operating Systems
Linux • Windows Server

Software

MySQL • Docker • Hyper-V • apache • nginx • WordPress

Office Software

Word • Excel (VBA, Power Pivot, Power Query) • PowerPoint • LaTeX • Photoshop

COURSEWORK

Electrical Circuits & Instrumentation Electromechanical Devices & Power Processing

Structure & Properties of Materials Control of Properties of Materials Mechanics of Deformable Solids

ADDITIONAL INFO

Citizenship

Canadian & EU Citizenship (UK)

Interests

Computers • Aerospace • Robotics • Automotive

Links/Social Media Website: bentley.sh GitHub: cjbentley

LinkedIn: cameron-bentley

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I am a highly motivated second-year Mechanical Engineering student with strong programming, design, & administration skills. I am ambitious to further develop my skills through challenging work and project experience, as well as to experience different industries and locations. I am capable of working in high-performance groups as both a leader and a member. My interests and skills are focused around computer hardware and software, aerospace, and automation.

EXPERIENCE

AECON GROUP INC. | Engineering Intern

May 2017 - August 2017 | Fort St. John, BC

- On-site intern during a gas cogeneration facility turnaround operation.
- Assisted with project controls, planning, scheduling, QC, and reporting.
- Developed red line corrections and P&ID's for in-field revisions to IFC drawings.
- Automated reporting and other office processes with Power Pivot and VBA.

WATSAT SATELLITE DESIGN TEAM | STRUCTURES SUBSYSTEM LEAD September 2016 – Present | Waterloo, ON

- Designed components for CubeSat satellite structural redesign.
- Collaborated with other subsystems to integrate attitude control hardware and communications antennas into the satellite frame.
- Documented and simulated structural design properties for presentation at the Canadian Satellite Design Challenge's CDR (Critical Design Review).
- Developed understanding of DFM and designing to specification (maximizing resistance to stress while minimizing weight and cost to manufacture).

PROJECTS

AIM ENGINEERING CHALLENGE | 1ST PLACE GROUP LEADER

January 2016 - May 2016 | Calgary, AB

- Challenge set by Alta Injection Molding (AIM) to improve the design of a reusable coffee pod for a Keurig machine.
- Developed & tested a new prototype and presented this prototype to the competition host.
- Group placed first; company integrated suggested changes into new pod design.

AUTOMATED FORKLIFT MODEL | GROUP MEMBER

January 2017 - April 2017 | Waterloo, ON

- Developed a model automated forklift for a course project, capable of sorting inventory into different colour coded areas (written in RobotC).
- Received score of 5/5 for robot performance.

CERTIFICATIONS

2017 H₂S Alive 2017 WHMIS

AWARDS

2016 President's Scholarship University of Waterloo
 2016 Alexander Rutherford Scholarship West Island College